(
"ai_sub_version": "1.9.2",
"subtitles_prompt_version": 2,
"complete": true,
"max_retries_exceeded": false,
"settings": (
"ai": (
"model": "gemini-cli:gemini-3-flash-preview",
"rpm": 4,
"tpm": 250000,
"google": (
"file_cache_ttl": 10,
"use_files_api": true
),
"gemini_cli": (
"timeout": 600
)
),
"split": (
"max_seconds": 300,
"re_encode": (
"enabled": true,
"fps": 1,
"height": 360,
"bitrate_kb": 35,
"encoder": "libx264"
)
),
"thread": (
"uploads": 4,
"re_encode": 2,
"subtitles": 8
),
"retry": (
"run": 3,
"max": 9,
"delay": 30
),
"log": (
"level": "info",
"timestamps": false,
"scrub": true
)
hololive production COUNTDOWN LIVE 2022▷2023 -hololive side-
ときのそら
Tokino Sora
ロボ子さん
Robocosan
AZKi
さくらみこ
Sakura Miko
星街すいせい
Hoshimachi Suisei
hololive production COUNTDOWN LIVE 2022▷2023 - hololive side -
ミックスナッツ
Mixed Nuts
袋に詰められたナッツのような
In a world like nuts packed
世間では
in a bag,
誰もがそれぞれ出会った誰かと
everyone is snuggling up
寄り添い合ってる
with someone they met.
そこに紛れ込んだ
We, who have
僕らはピーナッツみたいに
blended in there, are like peanuts.
木の実のふりしながら
Pretending to be tree nuts
微笑み浮かべる
while wearing a smile.
幸せのテンプレートの上
On the template of happiness,
文字通り絵に描いたうわべのうた
literally a song of a painted-on façade.
テーブルを囲み手を合わす
Even when gathered around the table
その時さえ ありのままでは居られないまま
and clapping hands, we can't be as we truly are.
隠し事だらけ
Full of secrets,
継ぎ接ぎだらけのホーム、ユーノウ？
full of patches, home, you know?
噛み砕いても無くならない
Even if chewed up, it won't disappear,
本音が歯に挟まったまま
the true feelings remain stuck in the teeth.
不安だらけ 成り行き任せのライフ
Full of anxiety, a life left to chance.
La la la...
借り初めまみれの日常だけど
In this daily life full of temporary things
ここに僕がいて あなたがいる
I am here, and you are here
この真実だけでも 胃がもたれていく
Even just this truth is giving me heartburn
化けの皮剥がれた一粒のピーナッツみたいに
Like a single peanut with its disguise peeled off
世間から一瞬で弾き出されてしまう そんな時こそ
When I'm instantly cast out by society, that's precisely when...
曲がりなりでよかったらそばにいさせて
If it's alright even if I'm flawed, let me stay by your side
共にいられ 揺られ 踏まれても
If we can be together, swayed and stepped on,
割れない殻みたいになったら
and become like an unbreakable shell
生まれた場所が木の上か地面の中か それだけの違い
Whether the place of birth was up on a tree or in the ground, that's the only difference
許されないほどにドライなこの世界を
May the rain evenly dampen this world
等しく雨が湿らせますように
that's unforgivably dry
時に冷たくて 騒がしい窓の向こう
Beyond the window that's sometimes cold and noisy
星のひとつも見つからない
Not even a single star can be seen
雷鳴見た日があってもいい
Even if there's a day when lightning strikes, it's fine
ミスだらけ アドレナリン 任せのショー
A show full of mistakes and fueled by adrenaline
La la la...
所詮ひと粒の日常だから
Because it's just a single grain of daily life
腹の中にでも 流して寝よう
Let's just swallow it down and go to sleep
隠し事だらけ 継ぎ接ぎだらけの
Full of secrets, full of patches
とっておきも出来損ないも
Devouring both the special things and the failures
残さずに全部食らいながら
without leaving anything behind
普通などない正解などない
There is no such thing as normal, no such thing as a correct answer
借り初めまみれの日常だけど
In this daily life full of temporary things
ここに僕がいて あなたがいる
I am here, and you are here
この真実だけでも 胃がもたれていく
Even just this truth is giving me heartburn
この一掴みの奇跡を 噛み締めていく
I'll keep savoring this handful of miracles
Woo!
アイデンティティ
作詞・作曲: Kanaria
歌: 癒月ちょこ、ときのそら、鷹嶺ルイ、ラプラス・ダークネス、百鬼あやめ
Identity
Lyrics & Music: Kanaria
Vocals: Yuzuki Choco, Tokino Sora, Takane Lui, La+ Darknesss, Nakiri Ayame
あっ、今日、君に伝えればなにかがあったような
Ah, today, if I told you, it felt like there was something
結成 真逆の踊るベース逆さまにして
Forming, the complete opposite of dancing bass turned upside down
恋とは魅惑のフラフラ舞う
Love is a mesmerizing, dizzying dance
ただ立ち尽くめここから息つく間
Just standing still, from here without a moment to catch my breath
アイデンティティ それは自己のアイデンティティ
Identity, that is one's own identity
アイデンティティ 唸れ 君ひとりのサイ
Identity, roar, your unique cry
まだ捨てないで待って それはひとつふたつのデスティニー
Don't throw it away yet, wait; that's one or two destinies
繋げてハッピー 落ちる流れ星と歪なあの星
Connect it to be happy, with the falling stars and that distorted star
La la la...
重なる面影に寄り添う そっと君に寄り添う
Drawing close to the overlapping silhouettes, softly drawing close to you
弾けだす視界 胸に飛び込むハート
The vision bursts forth, a heart leaping into the chest,
刻むあなたのアイデンティティ
carving out your identity
舐めププライド 飛び込めデンジャラス
Lick-play pride, dive in, dangerous
さっと羽ばたく強気な狂気と
Flapping wings quickly with bold madness
そんで裏切りお涙頂戴
And then betrayal, seeking sympathy
La la la...
きっと恋とは真逆のフラフラ舞う
Surely love is the complete opposite, a dizzying dance
ただ立ち尽くめここから息つく間
Just standing still, from here without a moment to catch my breath
アイデンティティ それは希望のアイデンティティ
Identity, that is the identity of hope
アイデンティティ 唸れ 君ひとりのサイ
Identity, roar, your unique cry
まだ捨てないで待って それはひとつふたつのデスティニー
Don't throw it away yet, wait; that's one or two destinies
すぐさまハッピー 落ちる流れ星と歪なあの星
Instantly happy, with the falling stars and that distorted star
La la la...
重なる面影に寄り添う そっと君に寄り添う
Drawing close to the overlapping silhouettes, softly drawing close to you
弾けだす視界 胸に飛び込むハート
The vision bursts forth, a heart leaping into the chest,
刻むあなたのアイデンティティ
carving out your identity
シャル・ウィ・ダンス？
Shall We Dance?
ミー・アーム・ハイ・ハー
Me-Arm-Hi-Her
悲しみは笑いましょう
Let's laugh through our sorrows
生きるってマリオネット
Living is like being a marionette
心臓がスイングしたら
If your heart starts to swing
ご機嫌はいかが？
How are you feeling?
アン・ドゥ、アン・ドゥ、アン・ドゥ・トロワ
Un, deux, un, deux, un, deux, trois
私うまく踊れないわ
I can't dance very well
痛みも恨みも悲しみも
Pain, resentment, and even sadness
混ぜて
Mix them up
捏ねて
Knead them
おやすみのキス
A goodnight kiss
シャル・ウィ・ダンス？　踊りましょう
Shall we dance? Let's dance
絶望　欲望　This is the life
Despair, desire, this is the life
シャドウ・ライフ
Shadow life
余計なこと考えないで一つになりましょう
Don't think too much, let's become one
いいな
It's nice
人間って
Being human
いいな
It's nice
La la la...
泣きたいのに笑っちゃう
I want to cry, but I end up laughing
人生ってピエロ
Life is like a clown
本当の心隠して
Hiding my true heart
笑うふりはするの
I pretend to laugh
アン・ドゥ、アン・ドゥ、アン・ドゥ・トロワ
Un, deux, un, deux, un, deux, trois
私うまく生きれないわ
I can't live very well
骨も嘘も不安も
Bones, lies, and even anxiety
溶かして
Dissolve them
燻して
Smoke them out
おやすみなさい
Goodnight
シャル・ウィ・ドリーム？　夢見ましょう
Shall we dream? Let's dream
寝ても覚めても　This is the life
Asleep or awake, this is the life
シャドウ・ライフ
Shadow life
目を閉じて嫌なこと全部全部忘れましょう
Close your eyes and forget every single bad thing
シャル・ウィ・ダンス？　不器用でも
Shall we dance? Even if we're clumsy
抗いて　もがいて　This is the life
Resist, struggle, this is the life
シャドウ・ステップ
Shadow step
余計なこと考えないでステップを踏み鳴らせ
Don't think too much, just stomp your steps
シャル・ウィ・スマイル？　今だけは
Shall we smile? Just for now
一緒に笑ってみませんか？
Won't you try laughing with me?
シャドウ・ダンス　今だけは
Shadow dance, just for now
全部忘れて一緒に跳びましょう
Forget everything and let's jump together
シャル・ウィ・ダンス？　踊りましょう
Shall we dance? Let's dance
絶望　欲望　This is the life
Despair, desire, this is the life
シャドウ・ライフ
Shadow life
余計なこと考えないで一つになりましょう
Don't think too much, let's become one
いいな
It's nice
人間って　いいな
Being human is nice
いいな
It's nice
人間って　人間って　いいな
Being human, being human, it's nice
いいな
It's nice
La la la...
チキチキバンバン
Chiki Chiki Ban Ban
ミー・アーム・ハイ・ハー
Me-Arm-Hi-Her
チャンチャン　アチキチキバンバン
Chan chan achiki chiki ban ban
アチキチキバンバン　アチキチキちゃんちゃん
アチキチキバンバン　アチキチキチキバンバン
A-chiki chiki bam bam, a-chiki chiki chan chan
A-chiki chiki bam bam, a-chiki chiki chiki bam bam
召しませテキーラ　みんな気まぐれ連れ
Have some tequila, everyone's a whimsical companion
言えばテキーラ　上がる妄想族でピカ
If you say tequila, it's flashy with the rising delusion group
夢はパンドラ　ほら贅沢なり
Dreams are Pandora, see how luxurious they are
みんな消しだしてバリトゥライ
Everyone erase it and it's party time
今夜はピエロ　昇れりゃ分からない
Tonight I'm a clown, you won't know if I can climb up
ケセラ週末の宿命
Que sera, the fate of the weekend
ちゃんちゃんアチキチキバンバン
何ももったいぶらず楽しめバリトゥライ
Chan chan, a-chiki chiki bam bam
Enjoy without holding anything back, it's party time
ちゃんちゃんアチキチキバンバン
何度もしゃくしゃくしたってバリトゥライ
Chan chan, a-chiki chiki bam bam
No matter how many times you crunch, it's party time
ちゃんちゃんアチキチキバンバン
愚か者ほど背徳感に感謝
Chan chan, a-chiki chiki bam bam
The more foolish they are, the more they appreciate the sense of immorality
ちゃんちゃんアチキチキバンバン
みんなスーパースターの卵さバリトゥライ
Chan chan, a-chiki chiki bam bam
Everyone's the egg of a superstar, it's party time
グラス　クラッシュしたい　でももだけでも
みんないらないヘンザ
I want to crash the glass, even if just for a bit
Everyone don't need it, hands up
ビリビリしたい　ジャパニーズプリティ
いざかりは沸騰
I want to feel a sting, Japanese pretty
The hunt is now boiling
グラス　クラッシュしたい　飲めばノリよく
開け放たせズイェー
I want to crash the glass, drink it for a good vibe
Let it wide open, yes
ステップ踏んでいこう　夢巻きしまむ
熱くダンシング・オー・イェー
Let's take steps, wrapping dreams around
Hot dancing, oh yeah
どうせこうして臆病風だ
投げをめざして一千本テキーラ
Anyway, doing this is like a cowardly wind
Aiming for a throw of a thousand tequilas
三千空だ空飛ぶじゅうたん
なすすべもなく下向かないで
Three thousand skies, a flying carpet
Don't look down with nothing to do
陰気じゃダメ　インフレしたまえ
ダラダラ狂われエンディング人生
Gloomy is no good, let it inflate
Go crazy lazily, life's ending
未練はNO　シャイニング軌道
張り切り肉射全力全
No regrets, a shining orbit
Energetic and at full power
オー・ベイビー　恥ずかしにははは
一切合切キラー
Oh baby, in embarrassment ha ha ha
An all-out killer
前だけ向いていいでしょ
燃えさかっちゃっていいでしょ
It's fine to only look forward
It's fine to burn up
もしもしプレイグラウンド　もしもしべいびー
熱くフルグル駆け巡る東大
Hello playground, hello baby
Hotly spinning around Tokyo University
ハラハラ時間にスポット当てな
いつまでドキドキ八時間
Spotlight the suspenseful time
How long will the excitement last, eight hours
ちゃんちゃんアチキチキバンバン　ちゃんちゃんアチキチキちゃんちゃん
アチキチキバンバン　アチキチキチキバンバン
Chan chan, a-chiki chiki bam bam, chan chan, a-chiki chiki chan chan
A-chiki chiki bam bam, a-chiki chiki chiki bam bam
ちゃんちゃんアチキチキバンバン
愚か者ほど背徳感に感謝
Chan chan, a-chiki chiki bam bam
The more foolish they are, the more they appreciate the sense of immorality
ちゃんちゃんアチキチキバンバン
みんなスーパースターの卵さバリトゥライ
Chan chan, a-chiki chiki bam bam
Everyone's the egg of a superstar, it's party time
ちゃんちゃんアチキチキバンバン　ちゃんちゃんアチキチキちゃんちゃん
アチキチキバンバン　アチキチキチキバンバン
Chan chan, a-chiki chiki bam bam, chan chan, a-chiki chiki chan chan
A-chiki chiki bam bam, a-chiki chiki chiki bam bam
Next...
Special Act - II
hololive English
hololive ENGLISH
小鳥遊キアラ　ワトソン・アメリア
森カリオペ　がうる・ぐら
Takanashi Kiara, Watson Amelia
Mori Calliope, Gawr Gura
剥がれ落ちたメイク　スッピンのアニマル
醜くたっていいじゃんのよ
The makeup has peeled off, a bare-faced animal
It's fine even if it's ugly, isn't it?
お座りとかできない　だって待てとかできない
喉鳴らして行っちゃうまで
I can't sit, because I can't wait
Until I go off purring
ガブッとしようか　高鳴るビート
芋もあどいも全然しよ
Shall we take a big bite? The throbbing beat
Let's do both bad things and innocent things
はまってみようか　ド派手なゲート
会いに来たいわ　秘密だよ
Shall we try getting hooked? A flashy gate
I want to come and see you, it's a secret
ねえ　止まれないほどに狂いたい
心があららら落ちちゃったのよ
Hey, I want to go crazy to the point I can't stop
My heart has gone fallen down, oh my
いたずらもし愛せたら　あたしは幸せです
If you could even love my mischief, I am happy
剥がれ落ちたメイク　スッピンのアニマル
醜くたっていいじゃんのよ
The makeup has peeled off, a bare-faced animal
It's fine even if it's ugly, isn't it?
お座りとかできない　だって待てとかできない
喉鳴らして行っちゃうまで
I can't sit, because I can't wait
Until I go off purring
牙を剥き出して　ズッキュンだ
あたしを手にしたら離さないでね
Baring my fangs, it's a 'zukkyun'
Once you have me, don't let go
剥がれ落ちたメイク　スッピンのアニマル
醜くたっていいじゃんのよ
The makeup has peeled off, a bare-faced animal
It's fine even if it's ugly, isn't it?
剥がれちゃってよ　狂っちゃってよ
殴っちゃってよ　むらっはっはっは
Get peeled off, go crazy
Get punched, mu la la la la
剥がれちゃってよ　狂っちゃってよ
めぐっちゃってよ　むらっはっはっはっは
Get peeled off, go crazy
Go around, mu la la la la la
やいやいやい　後悔なんてつまんない
せめてちょっとは踏んでほしかったのよ
Ya ya ya, regrets are boring
At least I wanted you to step on me a little
あちらだけ欲張れるなら
If only that side can be greedy
あたしは幸せに　なりたいです
I want to be happy
はがれ落ちたメイク おスッピンのアニマル
Fallen makeup, an animal bare-faced
醜くてもやっちゃうのよ
Even if it's ugly, I'll do it
お座りとかできなくたって 待てもできないの
I can't sit, and I can't stay
喉鳴らしてイっちゃうまで
Until I'm purring and let go
塗り重ねたメイクはバッチリなアニマル
Layered makeup, a perfect animal
目を見開いて待ってるのよ
With eyes wide open, I'm waiting
お座りとかできなくたって 待てもできないの
I can't sit, and I can't stay
喉鳴らしてイっちゃうまで
Until I'm purring and let go
牙を出し叫べ ズッキュンダ
Bare your fangs and shout, bang!
私に噛みついたら離さないんだ
Once you bite me, I won't let go
塗り重ねたメイクはバッチリなアニマル
Layered makeup, a perfect animal
目をひん剥いて待ってるのよ
With eyes wide open, I'm waiting
ニャオーン ウニャー シャシャシャ シャシャシャ
Nyaon unya Sha-sha-sha sha-sha-sha
ニャオーン ウニャー ニャニャニャニャニャニャニャニャ
Nyaon unya Nya-nya-nya-nya-nya-nya-nya-nya
ニャオーン ウニャー シャシャシャ シャシャシャ
Nyaon unya Sha-sha-sha sha-sha-sha
One Two Get you! 熱烈 Watch you!
One Two Get you! Passionately watching you!
好きすぎて弾けたビビビマインド
Too much love, popping heart
ルーレット急騰 ストップ火をつけた
Roulette surging, stop, set on fire
いぞいぞいぞ
Izzo izzo izzo
H Q S Q トキメキな Q
H Q S Q, a heart-pounding Q
1ミリの隙間にダイビング
Diving into a 1mm gap
まぶたごと全部コンプリート Up and Up
All eyelids complete, Up and Up
いぞいぞいぞいぞ せーの！
Izzo izzo izzo izzo Ready, set!
さて今日はもっとメンタル
Now today, more mental
不等式チャレンジ
Inequality challenge
ちょっとだけセンチメンタル
Just a little sentimental
だいしきゅーだいしゅき 1 2 3 ハイ！
URGENTLY LOVE YOU, 1 2 3 High!
マミムメモメロメロ見れないの
Ma-mi-mu-me-mo-melo-melo, I can't look
タチツテトテトテト手が触れて
Ta-chi-tsu-te-to-te-to-te-to, hands touching
だいしきゅーだいしゅきになれ
Urgently love me more
もっとキュキュキュキュ求愛せよ
Court me more and more
アマネクリサーチつけてるハート
Universal research, attached heart
でもねこの胸に嘘つかないで
But please don't lie to this heart
だいしきゅーだいしゅきになれ
Urgently love me more
私じゃないなんて終わってんね
It's not me? That's just wrong
One Two Get you! 満悦 Watch you!
One Two Get you! Delighted to watch you!
好きすぎて空っぽ強靭マインド
Too much love, empty, strong mind
ルーレットちょっとストップいざ求愛
Roulette, stop a bit, now court me
いやいやいやでもせーの！
No, no, no, but ready, set!
さて今日はもっと愛でて
Now today, adore me more
うるわしきチャレンジ
Beautiful challenge
パッとかいたオートメーション
Quickly drawn automation
だいしきゅーだいしゅき 1 2 3 ハイ！
URGENTLY LOVE YOU, 1 2 3 High!
マミムメロメロにして欲しいの
I want you to be ma-mi-mu-melo-melo
ナニヌネコメコメ恋の子猫さん
Na-ni-nu-ne-ko-me-ko-me, a kitten in love
だいしきゅーだいしゅきになれ
Urgently love me more
もっとキキキキ求愛せよ
Court me more and more
あまねくマリオネット操れレイディ
Universal marionette, control me lady
でもねそれもね悪くはないね
But hey, that's not too bad either
だいしきゅーだいしゅきになれ
Urgently love me more
私じゃないなんて終わってんね
It's not me? That's just wrong
ボレロにな魔法にして
Make it a bolero magic
周波数を乱さないで
Don't disturb the frequency
曰く付きの魅惑のリップ
Tainted, alluring lips
リアルになるビナー
Becoming real inner
マミムメモメロメロ見れないの
Ma-mi-mu-me-mo-melo-melo, I can't look
タチツテトテトテト手が触れて
Ta-chi-tsu-te-to-te-to-te-to, hands touching
だいしきゅーだいしゅきになれ
Urgently love me more
もっとキュキュキュキュ求愛せよ
Court me more and more
アマネクリサーチつけてるハート
Universal research, attached heart
でもねこの胸に嘘つかないで
But please don't lie to this heart
だいしきゅーだいしゅきになれ
Urgently love me more
私じゃないなんて終わってんね
It's not me? That's just wrong
終わってんね
It's wrong
マミムメモメロメロ見れないの
Ma-mi-mu-me-mo-melo-melo, I can't look
タチツテトテトテト手が触れて
Ta-chi-tsu-te-to-te-to-te-to, hands touching
だいしきゅーだいしゅきになれ
Urgently love me more
もっとキュキュキュキュ求愛せよ
Court me more and more
アマネクリサーチつけてるハート
Universal research, attached heart
でもねこの胸に嘘つかないで
But please don't lie to this heart
だいしきゅーだいしゅきになれ
Urgently love me more
私じゃないなんて終わってんね
It's not me? That's just wrong
パクっとしたいわ 端から端まで結ばれたいな
I want to take a bite, I want to be tied from end to end
パクっとしたいわ 指先と言葉で伝えたいな
I want to take a bite, I want to tell you with fingertips and words
パクっとしたいわ 悪ふざけかもしれないお遊びで
I want to take a bite, maybe just playing around for fun
パクっとしたいわ どっちがどっちにしたいな
I want to take a bite, wondering which one wants which
ただただ問答 間違ってんのはどっち？
Just a question, which one is wrong?
え、スマイルは0円？
Eh, a smile is 0 yen?
何回でも どんなことがあっても幸せそうです
No matter how many times, no matter what happens, they look happy.
あー 猛烈に愛してくれ サンダーガッデス ムービー
Ah, love me fiercely, Thunder Goddess Movie.
冗談めいた本当のセリフに 誰が気づいてんだ
Who noticed the true lines hidden in the jokes?
冗談めいた言葉で案外 本心なんです
In joking words, it's actually my true heart.
だって歌ってそういうもんでしょって ネットの掲示板で読んだよ
Because I read on an online bulletin board that's just what songs are.
腐ってる日常 なんとか生きてて
In this rotten daily life, somehow managing to live.
そうかもしれない どうとか思うけど これが私 あー言えば、こういう
That might be so, whatever I think, this is me. If you say this, I say that.
ぱくっとしたいわ 端から端まで結ばれたいな
I want to take a bite, I want to be tied from end to end.
ぱくっとしたいわ 指先と言葉で伝えたいな
I want to take a bite, I want to convey with fingertips and words.
ぱくっとしたいわ 我儘かもしれない アンサーです
I want to take a bite, it might be selfish, but it's my answer.
ぱくっとしたいわ どっちもどっちにしたいな
I want to take a bite, I want to make it six of one and half a dozen of the other.
ドキドキ 踊りダンスに洗練 凛として 身動き取れないの 怠惰 怠惰
Thump-thump. Refined in the dance. Dignified. I can't move, laziness, laziness.
It doesn't matter matter 違反とディスコミュニケーション プレイ状況
It doesn't matter matter, violation and discommunication, play status.
あー 全然ないロケーション 鑑定ルーティン
Ah, a location that doesn't exist at all, appraisal routine.
生絞りの完結系オン Destiny 抜いただけギュッパッピ
Freshly squeezed complete system on, Destiny, just pulled it out, gyu-pa-pi.
吐息完成 立って終わんない問題です
Sigh complete. It's a problem that won't end even if I stand.
つーか 実感 元も無くなって終わってる現在進行形かも
Wait, the actual feeling is gone from the start, maybe it's ending in the present continuous.
フラットな感情 どこかに行っちゃった
Flat emotions have gone off somewhere.
宝箱だって 出るつもりもないのにさ あー言えば、こういう
Even the treasure chest has no intention of coming out. If you say this, I say that.
ぱくっとしたいわ 端から端まで結ばれたいな
I want to take a bite, I want to be tied from end to end.
ぱくっとしたいわ 指先と言葉で伝えたいな
I want to take a bite, I want to convey with fingertips and words.
ぱくっとしたいわ 我儘かもしれない アンサーです
I want to take a bite, it might be selfish, but it's my answer.
ぱくっとしたいわ どっちもどっちにしたいな
I want to take a bite, I want to make it six of one and half a dozen of the other.
ぱくっとしたいわ 音から意味まで結ばれたいな
I want to take a bite, I want to be tied from sound to meaning.
ぱくっとしたいわ 確かな言葉で見つからないや
I want to take a bite, I can't find it with certain words.
ぱくっとしたいわ 各々から繋がるアンサーで
I want to take a bite, with the answer connecting from each of us.
ぱくっとしたいわ どっちもどっちにしたいな
I want to take a bite, I want to make it six of one and half a dozen of the other.
DADDY ! DADDY ! DO ! 欲しいのさ あなたのすべてが
DADDY ! DADDY ! DO ! I want it. Every part of you.
愛に抱かれ ギラギラ 燃えてしまいたい
Embraced by love, sparkling, I want to burn away.
可愛げなキスで (One, Two, Three) 目線逸らして ずるいよね
With a charming kiss (One, Two, Three), you look away. That's unfair, isn't it?
火照りだす僕の気持ち もて遊ぶみたいで
It feels like you're playing with my burning feelings.
追いかけちゃダメなのは分かってる でも無理さ
I know I shouldn't chase you. But I can't help it.
一度踏み出せば戻れなくて 仮面は脱ぎ捨てて 往(い)けない
Once I take a step forward, I can't go back. I can't go on without casting off this mask.
言葉で 遊びがマジになる
With words, this game becomes serious.
DADDY ! DADDY ! DO ! 欲しいのさ あなたのすべてが
DADDY ! DADDY ! DO ! I want it. Every part of you.
騙されたら それでもいい もっと震わせて
If I'm deceived, that's fine too. Make me tremble more.
見せてくれ 僕だけに 笑顔の裏まで
Show me, and only me. Even the side behind your smile.
愛に抱かれ ギラギラ 燃えてしまいたい
Embraced by love, sparkling, I want to burn away.
躊躇などしない (No No No) 二度と会えない人だから
I won't hesitate (No No No) because you're someone I'll never meet again.
後悔にくれるのなら 恋の火に焼かれたい
If I'm to be lost in regret, I'd rather be burned by the flames of love.
わざとでしょ？ 泣いた瞳が 愛おしさ刺激する
You're doing it on purpose, right? Your teary eyes stimulate my affection.
そっと振り返る美しさに 心は掴まれて 呼吸が止まって
My heart is captured by the beauty of you turning back, and my breath stops.
遊びがマジになる
This game becomes serious.
DADDY ! DADDY ! DO ! ぶつけたい 想いのすべてを
DADDY ! DADDY ! DO ! I want to unleash all of my feelings.
綺麗なままじゃなくて 危険な願いも
Not just the pure ones, but even the dangerous wishes.
止めないで その声が 僕を連れて行く
Don't stop it. That voice takes me away.
愛に抱かれ ギラギラ 燃えてしまいたい
Embraced by love, sparkling, I want to burn away.
あなただけと行く
I'll go only with you.
君に響くわ
It resonates with you
優しく微笑む度
Every time you smile gently
飲み込まれて
I'm swallowed up
誘われて
I'm invited
未知の世界
Into an unknown world
触れて
Touch me
Oh!
DADDY! DADDY! DO!
最後まで あなたに委ねて
Entrusting myself to you until the end
壊れるなら それでもいい
If I break, that's fine too
もっと狂わせて
Drive me more crazy
見せてくれ 僕だけに
Show me, only to me
心の奥まで
Deep into your heart
愛に抱かれ ギラギラ 燃えたい
Embraced by love, I want to burn brightly
命果てる...
Until life ends...
...夜明けまで
...until dawn
Pa pa pa pa...
Next...
Special Collaboration - 1
hololive × HOLOSTARS
AZKi / ときのそら / 律可
AZKi / Tokino Sora / Rikka
勿忘
Wasurena
例えば今君がその瞳
Even if your eyes right now
作詞：atagi, PORIN 作曲：atagi, RYO NAGANO
Lyrics: atagi, PORIN / Composition: atagi, RYO NAGANO
濡らしていたとしても
were wet with tears,
呼ぶ声はもう聞こえない
I can no longer hear the voice calling out.
絵の具を溶かすように 君との日々は
Like dissolving paint, the days with you
記憶の中に滲んでいく
are blurring into my memories.
何かを求めれば 何かが
If I seek something, something
こぼれ落ちていく そんなこの世界で
will spill away, in such a world.
春の風を待つあの花のように
Like that flower waiting for the spring breeze,
君という光があるのなら
if there is a light called you,
巡り巡る運命を超えて
crossing over the turning wheels of fate,
咲かせよう 愛の花を 花束を
let's make the flowers of love bloom, a bouquet.
願いが叶うのなら 二人の世界
If my wish comes true, I want to live
また生きてみたい
in our world once again.
あのキスから芽吹く日々
The days sprouting from that kiss,
見つめ直す 花びらも 香りも忘れて
looking back again, forgetting the petals and scent.
君への想い 枯れていく
My feelings for you are withering away.
散ってしまいそうな心に
To my heart that's about to scatter,
覚えたての愛の美しさを ねえ 咲かせて
please, make the beauty of love I've just learned bloom.
春の風を待つあの花のように
Like that flower waiting for the spring breeze,
飾らない心でいられたら
if I could be with an unadorned heart,
触れられなくても 想い煩っても
even if I can't touch you, even if I'm troubled,
忘れないよ この香りを 一つずつ
I won't forget this scent, one by one.
...つなぎ合わせて
...joining them together
君という光があるのなら
If there is a light that is you
巡り巡る
Going round and round
運命を超えて
Beyond fate
咲かせるさ
I'll make them bloom
愛の花を
The flowers of love
花束を
A bouquet
Next...
星街すいせい　奏手イヅル　アステル・レダ
Suisei Hoshimachi / Izuru Kanade / Astel Leda
誰もが突如に始まった
It started suddenly for everyone
シネマ
作詞・作曲:Ayase
Cinema
Lyrics/Composition: Ayase
でたらめなシナリオの上で
On a nonsensical script
それは映画のような
It's like a movie
まるで映画のような
Just like a movie
どこにでもあるストーリー
A story you can find anywhere
間違いだらけの道のりだ
It's a journey full of mistakes
丸つけられるのはいくつだ
How many will be marked correct?
何が良くないのか
What is wrong?
どこが良くないのか
Where is it wrong?
そこまで教えてくれよ
Tell me that much
明け方の妄想 既聴感の逃避行と
Dawn's delusions, an escape from déjà vu,
勘違いの英雄ごっこ
and playing hero by mistake
もう渋滞してんだ どうしようもこうしようもないような
It's already congested, like there's nothing that can be done
こんなはずじゃなかったよなって
Thinking "it wasn't supposed to be like this"
どんなはずだったんだよなって
Wondering "how was it supposed to be?"
思えば思うほど
The more I think about it
いやこれじゃないない
No, this isn't it
はまり役悪いような
Like a bad typecast
向いてないない
I'm not suited for it
今すぐやめてしまうか
Should I quit right now?
そりゃないない
No way
いつになれば僕も主役になれるんだろうな
I wonder when I'll ever be the protagonist
手に付かなくなったり洗ったり
Getting distracted or washing my hands
増えた荷物数えて泣いたり
Counting my growing baggage and crying
期待するはずでもなくガッカリ
Not even expecting anything but still disappointed
責めることすらやめて淡々と
Giving up on even blaming myself, just indifferently
遠ざかる街の明かり 燦々としてる
The distant city lights are sparkling brilliantly
あの通りすがり
That passerby
始めるなら今 そうだな
If I'm starting, it's now, right?
やろう やろう やろう
Let's do it, let's do it, let's do it
いやこれじゃないない
No, this isn't it
はまり役悪いような
Like a bad typecast
向いてないない
I'm not suited for it
今すぐやめてしまえば
If I were to quit right now
でも何万回と繰り返して
But repeating it tens of thousands of times
明日に期待してしまうんだ
I end up expecting something from tomorrow
明け方の妄想 既聴感の逃避行と
Dawn's delusions, an escape from déjà vu,
勘違いの英雄ごっこ
and playing hero by mistake
もう渋滞してんだ どうしようもこうしようもないような
It's already congested, like there's nothing that can be done
あの頃は確かにあったんだ
There certainly was a time back then
描き出したものがあったんだ
Something I had drawn out
いつの間にか僕は
Before I knew it, I...
誰もが突如に始まった
It started suddenly for everyone
でたらめなシナリオの上で
On a nonsensical script
何かを演じるの?
Am I playing something?
誰かを演じるの?
Am I playing someone?
そんなわけがないだろう
There's no way that's it
待ってこれじゃない
Wait, this isn't it
まだここじゃないない
It's not here yet
終わりじゃないから
Because it's not the end
向いてないない
I'm not suited for it
なら書き換えてしまえよ
Then just rewrite it
ほら大胆 いつもいつでもきっと
Look, be bold, always and surely
主役は僕だけだろ
I'm the only protagonist, right?
いつの日かバイバイ
Someday, bye-bye,
終わりは来るから
because the end will come
拍手喝采 笑顔で会おう
Let's meet with thunderous applause and a smile
変えたい未来はここにあった
The future I want to change was right here
思うあまり隙間より
Through the gaps in my thoughts
これもそうだ
This too
最底辺から駆け上がった
I ran up from the absolute bottom
映画のようなストーリー
A story like a movie
Wow oh oh...
好きというのはロックだぜ!
作詞:秋元康 作曲:野村陽一郎
Suki to Iu no wa Rock daze!
Lyrics: Yasushi Akimoto / Comp: Yoichiro Nomura
好きというのはロックだぜ！
Suki to Iu no wa Rock daze!
#ホロライブカウントダウン
#hololivecountdown
Wow oh...
世界で一番
In the whole world,
僕が嫌いなのは 僕だと
the person I hate most is myself...
気づいた時から
...from the moment I realized that,
黙り込んでしまった
I've been keeping quiet.
友達なんかは
I never thought...
欲しいと思わなかった 私
...that I wanted any friends.
みんなに混じって
Just blending in with everyone,
何でも頷いた
I nodded at everything.
夢とか希望を
Rather than carrying...
背負うより 楽な方がいい
...dreams and hopes, I'd rather take it easy.
何も期待しないことが
Not expecting anything...
傷つかない未来
...is a future where I won't get hurt.
君を好きになった
I fell in love with you.
それだけのことでも
Even just that one thing...
すべてがひっくり返って
...has turned everything upside down,
キラキラ始めた
and it's all started to sparkle.
愛ってこんなにも
Is love really...
力があるのか
...this powerful?
僕は生まれ変わったんだ
I have been reborn.
好きになってくれ
Please fall in love with me.
Wow oh...
人はいつから
Since when are people...
大人と呼ばれてしまうのか
...called adults?
自分のことさえも
Still not even...
理解できないまま
...understanding myself.
何もやりたいことなんか
Even for me, who had...
なかった僕でも
...nothing I wanted to do,
君に会えるかもしれない
knowing I might get to see you...
明日が楽しみだ
...makes me look forward to tomorrow.
誰かを好きになる
Falling in love with someone...
やさしいことなのに
...is such a kind thing, and yet
運命的に出会わなきゃ
unless it's a fated encounter...
心は動かない
...my heart won't be moved.
この恋逃がしたら
If I let this love slip away,
青春は終わる
my youth will come to an end.
僕は僕を嫌いじゃない
I don't hate myself anymore.
好きになってくれ
Please fall in love with me.
心で感じた
I felt it in my heart.
こちらへと振り向かせたくなる
It makes me want to make you look my way.
願いの強さよ
The strength of my wish!
すべてをゼロにしてでも
Even if I have to reset everything to zero,
前しか見えない
I can only look forward.
全力で行くよ 情熱の近くまで
I'll go all out, until I'm close to passion!
答えが欲しい
I want an answer!
君を好きになった
I fell in love with you.
それだけのことでも
Even just that one thing...
すべてがひっくり返って
...has turned everything upside down,
キラキラ始めた
and it's all started to sparkle.
愛ってこんなにも
Is love really...
力があるのか
...this powerful?
僕は生まれ変わったんだ
I have been reborn.
好きになってくれ
Please fall in love with me.
君を
With you...
…痛いって泣いたって
...even if I say it hurts, even if I cry
好きになってくれ
please come to love me.
残響散歌
作詞：aimerrhythm　作曲：飛内将大
Zankyo Sanka
Lyrics: aimerrhythm  Composition: Masahiro Tobinai
誰が袖に咲く花か
Whose sleeve does this flower bloom on?
ただそこに藍を落とした
Simply dropping indigo there.
派手に色を溶かす夜に
In the night where colors dissolve showily,
銀朱の月を添えて
adding a silver-vermilion moon.
転がるように風を切って
Cutting through the wind as if rolling,
躓くごとに強くなって
becoming stronger with every stumble.
光も痛みも怒りも全部抱きしめて
Embracing all the light, pain, and anger.
選ばれなければ
If not chosen,
選べばいい
then just choose.
声よ轟け　夜のその向こうへ
Let my voice roar, towards the other side of the night.
涙で滲んでた　あんなに遠くの景色まで
Echo through to the scenery so far away
響き渡れ
that was blurred by tears.
何を奏でて？
What are you playing?
誰に届けたくて？
Who do you want to reach?
不確かなままでいい
It's okay to remain uncertain.
どんなに暗い感情も
No matter how dark the emotions,
どんなに長い葛藤も
no matter how long the conflict,
歌と散れ
scatter with the song,
残響
resonance.
ただ一人舞う千夜
Dancing all alone through a thousand nights.
違えない愛を結べば
If we tie an unchanging love,
派手な色も負かすように
so as to defeat even showy colors,
深紅の香こそあわれ
the deep crimson scent is truly moving.
この先の向こう辛い時も
Even during painful times beyond this,
口先よりも胸を張って
puff out your chest more than your words.
抱いた夢の灯を全部たどるだけ
Just tracing all the lights of the dreams you held.
逃げ出すためここまで来たんじゃないだろう？
You didn't come this far just to run away, right?
選ばれなければ
If not chosen,
選べばいい
then just choose.
声を枯らして燃える花のように
Like a flower that burns until its voice withers,
闇間を照らしたら
once you light up the darkness,
曖昧すぎる世界も不鮮明にして
make even the overly vague world indistinct.
夜を数えて朝を描くような
Like counting the nights and painting the morning,
鮮やかな音を鳴らせ
ring out a vivid sound.
どんなに深い後悔も
No matter how deep the regret,
どんなに高い限界も
no matter how high the limit,
掻き消して
drown it out,
残響
resonance.
踊
作詞：DECO*27　作曲：Giga, TeddyLoid
Odor
Lyrics: DECO*27  Composition: Giga, TeddyLoid
半端なら K.O.
If you're half-hearted, it's a K.O.
ふわふわしたいならどうぞ
If you want to feel lightheaded, go ahead.
開演準備しちゃおうか
Shall we get ready for the start of the show?
泣いても笑っても愛してね
Whether crying or laughing, love me, okay?
ほら、せーの
Look, ready, set,
手を鳴らせろ
let your hands ring out.
なんだかなってつまんないこともおるでしょう
It's somewhat boring, that kind of thing happens.
ロンリーロンリー
Lonely lonely
もっと本気出さなきゃ
You have to get more serious.
嫌になっちゃってのろり　バックハグだろか
Getting fed up and sluggish, is it a back hug?
溺れて落ちて
Drowning and falling.
もっと頑張って　あがるまでもっと頑張って
Try harder, try harder until you rise.
さあ、一人より二人　増えたら安心心配ないや
Come on, two is better than one, if the number increases, no need to worry.
オーライ任せてドンマイ　波より呑んじゃえ
Alright, leave it to me, don't mind, just swallow it down like a wave.
みんなで乗っかっちゃえば
If we all jump on board.
案外サクッといっちゃいそう
It seems like it'll go unexpectedly smoothly.
半端なら K.O.
If you're half-hearted, it's a K.O.
ふわふわしたいならどうぞ
If you want to feel lightheaded, go ahead.
開演準備しちゃおうか
Shall we get ready for the start of the show?
泣いても笑っても愛してね
Whether crying or laughing, love me, okay?
ほら、せーの
Look, ready, set,
手を鳴らせろ
let your hands ring out.
声を震わせて
Trembling my voice.
Wow wow...
取り出せ取り出せ　孤独はさっき舞い降りて
Take it out, take it out, loneliness alighted just now.
Wow wow...
闇まで教えて　ここらでバイバイレッツゴー
Tell me even about the darkness, bye-bye for now, let's go.
Gonna let go 感度と 泥騒去の化粧板で
Gonna let go, the thrill and the makeup board on the street corner
抑え込んで 突っ込んで しまっちゃうでしょ Yeah
Hold it back, shove it in, it'll happen, right? Yeah
半端ならテンション 寝舞っちゃってんの そんと
Half-done tension, I'm getting sleepy
ドバっと 吹き出すのは 本音の独り言
What's gushing out is a sincere monologue
別に興味ない No!
Not particularly interested, No!
特に関係ない No No!
Particularly unrelated, No No!
塞ぎ込んで 絶好調 絶壁上 Yeah
Feeling down, in top form, on a precipice Yeah
ノイズを奏でて フラフラ Proye
Playing the noise, dizzy fura fura proye
ふらつまって 夜風だ Yeah Yeah
Wandering in the night breeze, Yeah Yeah
泣いていこう
Let's cry out
Pa-Pa-Pa-Pa-Pa-Pa-Pa-Pa...
半端なら K.O.
If it's half-baked, it's K.O.
Woah woah woah woah...
取り出せ 取り出せ 此処は先舞い踊れ
Take it out, take it out, here we dance first
Woah woah woah woah...
今まで 教えて 超え山 温泉 Party
Until now, teach me, mountain-crossing hot spring party
Woah woah woah woah...
此の年を 刻もう
Let's engrave this year
Woah woah woah woah...
次まで お元気で 此処でバイバイ Let's go
Until next time, stay well, bye-bye from here, Let's go
いい加減 普通の年越しにも飽きたな
I'm getting tired of normal New Year's celebrations.
そうだ！ 年越しの瞬間 みんなでジャンプしよう！
I know! Let's all jump at the moment the year changes!
え〜、むず。 てかみんな集めんの無理くね？
Eh, that's hard. I mean, isn't it impossible to get everyone together?
あと3分で日付変わるし
The date changes in 3 minutes anyway.
そんなこともあろうかと！
I thought that might happen!
用意してるよ！ 時空は超越薬！
I've prepared it! Space-time transcendence medicine!
こよりだけで 世界征服できるよ
Koyori alone could conquer the world.
よし、その薬を使って 先輩達を呼んでくるんだ！
Right, use that medicine to call our seniors!
え〜！呼んで呼んで呼んで呼んで呼んで呼んで...
Eh! Call them, call them, call them, call them...!
いい加減諦めろ！
Just give up already!
まだまだ！
Not yet!
2023がいい！
2023 is good!
2023はダサいとか言うな！
Don't say 2023 is uncool!
来年はうさぎどしぺこなんだ！
Next year is the Year of the Rabbit, peko!
何やってるんですか？
What are you doing?
何やってると思う？
What do you think we're doing?
問題：これはいつの初日の出でしょーか？
Problem: When was this first sunrise?
わかるか！
How should I know!
カラー写真ってことは比較的最近？
A color photo means it's relatively recent?
真面目。
Serious.
今年ですね！
It's this year!
正解！
Correct!
Hey, look.
Pas banget.
Perfect.
Ah, oh, gitu.
Ah, oh, I see.
すごい力で握られたようね
It seems it was squeezed with incredible force.
大丈夫すか？
Are you okay?
逃さないよ〜
I won't let you go~
そんなとこ...
There...
おきおき... おかゆー...
Wakey wakey... Okayu...
起こさないといけないのか。
Do I have to wake them up?
フレア。
Flare.
ノエル。
Noel.
船長を一人にしないで！
Don't leave the Captain alone!
こよりがいますよ！
Koyori is here!
なんで追いかけてくんのよ！
Why are you chasing me!
なんで戦ってんのよ！
Why are you fighting!
世の中年末休暇だから！
Because it's the end of the year holiday for the world!
あれは我々のカルマが呼び寄せたアンチ...
That's an anti- called by our karma...!
やるわよ！
I'll do it!
なんで？なんでですか？
Why? Why?
ちょっとでも東に行って、みんなより早く年を越す！
Go a bit further east and cross the year before everyone else!
それがはあちゃまの流儀じゃ！
That's Haachama's way!
あのまま行けば事務所つくか。
If we keep going like that, we'll reach the office.
ギブギブギブギブ！
Give up, give up, give up, give up!
ファイト、ファイト！
Fight, fight!
ノーギブ。
No give.
ノーチョッピング。
No topping out.
まだやれるだろ！
You can still do it, right!
レフリー、レフリー！
Referee, referee!
Go go!
止めなくていいのかな...
Shouldn't we stop them...?
反省したか？
Have you reflected?
生きるためには頭数減らさないとな。
To live, we have to reduce the number of heads.
おまえが出てこないで！
Don't you come out!
粉みじんですか？
Is it into powder?
粉みじんです。
It's into powder.
アキロゼがしっかりしないと全滅だ。
If AkiRose doesn't stay firm, it's total annihilation.
お粉ですか？
Is it powder?
粉みじんです。
It's into powder.
これで揃ったな。
Now we're all together.
すみませんお付き合いいただいて。
Sorry for making you tag along.
10, 9, 8, 7, 6, 5, 4, 3, 2, 1, 0!
HAPPY NEW YEAR!
あ〜、やべ。
Ah, crap.
こんなことしていいでござるか？
Is it okay to be doing this?
怒られるじゃ済まないね。
Being scolded won't be enough.
落ちていく先輩たち可愛い！
The seniors falling are cute!
うわー！
Uwaa!
笑顔のサンライト
Sunlight of smiles
どんな暗闇の中でも 強いきらめき
A strong sparkle even in any darkness
君に届いているかな 一ミリでも
Is it reaching you? Even just a millimeter...
伝わればいい
...if it gets through, that's enough
チャージ チャレンジ 全力アクセル がんばる君へ
Charge, challenge, full throttle, to you doing your best
一番ノリノリのスマイルを送る 昴チャンネル
Sending the most upbeat smile, Subaru Channel
Every day, My day
みんなで！
Everyone together!
リンダンリンダン ここはビビッド
Ring-dong, ring-dong, it's vivid here
期待をもっと感じて
Feel more expectation
ジャンピンジャンピン いっぺんドタミン
Jumpin' jumpin', once with dotamine
お宝気分 爽快！
Treasure feeling, refreshing!
異論ハロは認めません
No objections allowed
史上最高の言葉 マイスタイル
The best words ever, my style
U & I ここがサレディ
U & I, here is the lady
ずっと見てて リリカモンザビート
Keep watching, Lyrica on the beat
どんな高い壁だって
No matter how high the wall
助走をつけて飛び越えて
I'll jump over it with a running start
誰も見たことない世界にみんなで行こう
Let's all go to a world no one has ever seen
君と Smile and Go 信じたもん勝ち
With you, Smile and Go, the one who believes wins
君と Smile and Go はじけたもん勝ち
With you, Smile and Go, the one who bursts out wins
ここに笑顔で集まれば 最高でしょ！
If we gather here with smiles, it's the best, right?
僕ら Smile and Go 持ってんでしょ？
We're Smile and Go, we have it, right?
僕ら Smile and Go 遊びまくろうぜ！
We're Smile and Go, let's play around!
この日常が大切な宝物
This daily life is a precious treasure
Smile and Go! Smile and Go!
なりたい僕を 君が好きな僕を
The me I want to be, the me you like
ちゃんと余りなく見せたいの
I want to show it all without leaving anything out
あちゃちゃ びっくりするほどできないや
Acha-cha, I can't do it to a surprising degree
間違って悩んだりばっかりじゃん
I'm always just worrying about mistakes
けど君に見つけて欲しくて
But I want you to find me
僕は君を迎えに行くんだ
So I'm coming to meet you
出会えたならハッピー
It's happy if we meet
わーお わーお 騒いじゃえ
Wa-o! Wa-o! Let's make a fuss
泣いて泣いて 愛して しっぽ振って
Cry, cry, love, and wag your tail
わーお わーお 騒いじゃえ
Wa-o! Wa-o! Let's make a fuss
駄目な僕をどうか覚えておいて
Please remember the bad me
もう君の心チクッとしちゃえ
I'll make your heart prickle already
大喝采だったらこっち来れば？
If it's great applause, why not come here?
派手な場所なんてさ 自分で作らなくちゃ
A flashy place, you have to make it yourself
これぞ最強だ ドラドラどーだ！
This is the strongest, how's that!
ありがた迷惑だ
It's an unwanted favor
ランランレンわー セケンエワー
run-ran-ren-wa, seken-e-wa
一進一退 毎日対戦
Ups and downs, matches every day
大成功のタレ流し
Leaking great success
笑えないなら笑え
If you can't laugh, laugh
ペコらなきゃ ペコらなきゃなんだかなぁ
If I don't Peko, if I don't Peko, what's with that
ペコらなきゃっちゃいたまい
If I don't Peko-ntcha-itai
ペコらなきゃなんだかなぁ
If I don't Peko, what's with that
ペコらなんなんなんやー
Peko-nan-nan-nan-ya
特殊世界一スーパーピンチピンチ
Special world's #1 super pinch pinch
ぶっちゃけ船長捕まえたくない？
To be honest, don't you want to catch the Captain?
予感予感だ トレジャーメイビーデスティニー
Hunch, it's a hunch, treasure maybe destiny
私の甘さが欲しいでしょ
You want my sweetness, right?
コンバンワ ホウショウマリンデス 秘宝を覗くわ
Good evening, I'm Houshou Marine, I'll peek at the secret treasure
コンバンワ ホウショウマリンデス 麗しくそして
Good evening, I'm Houshou Marine, beautifully and...
コンバンワ ホウショウマリンデス 恍惚の時を
Good evening, I'm Houshou Marine, a time of ecstasy
コンバンワ ホウショウマリンデス 早くしろ！
Good evening, I'm Houshou Marine, hurry up!
最果ての国に集えよ
Gather in the land at the end of the world
闇に震えケルベロス
Cerberus trembling in the dark
刹那に響く言葉は
The words that echo in the moment are
ブチギレ発狂パラダイス
Snap-mad madness paradise
キラリ心の奥底まで届け
Sparkle, reach to the bottom of your heart
これからも私の元で
From now on, stay with me
不思議な力 撃ち放って
Fire off that mysterious power
世界も笑顔になっちゃって
Making the world smile too
ウラタタパパラリラ
Uratatapapararira
いっしょ！ いっしょうたいより！
Together! I-I-I-Invitation!
さりげない合図に隠れて
Hiding in a casual signal
答えはすぐに分からせてあげる
I'll let you know the answer right away
余計な嘘にまみれた
Covered in unnecessary lies
言葉そのままに受け止めてあげる
I'll accept your words just as they are
さあ今宵闇に刻むこの名を
Now, this name engraved in the darkness tonight
分からせてあげる
I'll let you know
ほら 悲鳴を 聞かせてよ
Hey, let me hear your screams
夢見ないで
Don't dream
ほら聞かせて
Hey, let me hear
ねぇ もっと ねぇ もっと
Hey, more, hey, more
好きになってもらいたいの
I want you to love me
いつでもそう 私は 媚びずに
Always, without flattery
よそ見なんて 許さないわ
I won't allow you to look away
ねぇ ほら 夢中にさせちゃうわ
Hey, I'll make you crazy for me
ねぇ ずっと 好きがいいの
Hey, I want your love forever
心も体も染まって
My heart and body are dyed
不意に こっち向いて手を叩いて
Suddenly turn this way and clap your hands
あぁ もう 離さないから
Ah, I won't let go anymore
絶対に 絶対ね 絶対よ
Definitely, definitely, definitely
約束だよ
It's a promise
愛しちゃお もっと
Let's fall in love more
だって僕は星だから
Because I'm a star
ステラ ステラ
Stellar Stellar
そうさ 今 僕を歌わせて ステラ ステラ
That's right, now let me sing, Stellar Stellar
ありったけの輝きを
With all my brilliance
今宵 音楽はずっと ずっと 止まない
Tonight, the music will never, ever stop
そうさ 今 愛を歌わせて ステラ ステラ
That's right, now let me sing of love, Stellar Stellar
世界 宇宙の真ん中で
In the middle of the world, the universe
今宵 音楽はきっと きっと 止まない
Tonight, the music will surely, surely never stop
そうだ 僕がずっと 泣きたかったのは
That's right, what I wanted to cry about all this time
待って シンデレラじゃないさ
Wait, I'm not Cinderella
迎えにきたんだ まださ
I came to pick you up, not yet
そうだ僕は星だから
That's right, because I'm a star
ステラ ステラ
Stellar Stellar
明けましておめでとうございます！
Happy New Year!
千本桜
Senbonzakura
大胆不敵にハイカラ革命
Boldly and fearlessly, a high-collar revolution
磊々落々反戦国家
Open-hearted anti-war nation
日の丸印の二輪車転がし
Rolling a bicycle with the Hinomaru mark
悪霊退散 ICBM
Exorcism, ICBM
環状線を走り抜けて
Running through the loop line
東奔西走なんのその
Running east and west, so what
少年少女戦国無双
Boys and girls, Sengoku Musou
浮世のまにまに
According to the floating world
千本桜 夜に紛れ
Senbonzakura, disappearing into the night
君の声も届かないよ
Even your voice won't reach
此処は宴 鋼の檻
Here is a feast, a steel cage
その断頭台で見下ろして
Look down from that guillotine
三千世界 常世の闇
Three thousand worlds, darkness of the afterlife
嘆く唄も聞こえないよ
Even the song of lament cannot be heard
青藍の空 遥か彼方
Indigo sky, far, far away
その光線銃で打ち抜いて
Shoot through with that ray gun
千本桜
Senbonzakura
逆戦錬磨の見た目は将校
Hardened by countless battles, appearing like an officer
行ったり来たりの花魁道中
Coming and going in an Oiran procession
アイツもコイツも皆で集まれ
Gather everyone, this guy and that guy
聖者の行進 ワン・ツー・サン・シ
The march of the saints, one, two, three, four
禅定門を潜り抜けて
Passing through the Zen gate
安楽浄土 厄払い
The Pure Land of Bliss, warding off evil
きっと最後は
Surely at the end
大団円
The grand finale
拍手の合間に
In the midst of the applause
千本桜 夜に紛れ
A thousand cherry trees, blending into the night
君の声も届かないよ
Even your voice won't reach me
此処は宴 鋼の檻
Here is a feast, a cage of steel
その断頭台で見下ろして
Look down from that guillotine
三千世界 常世の闇
The entire universe, the darkness of the underworld
嘆く唄も聞こえないよ
Even the song of lament cannot be heard
青藍の空 遥か彼方
The indigo sky, far, far away
その光線銃を打ち上げろ
Fire that ray gun
環状線を走り抜けて
Running through the loop line
東奔西走なんのその
Tossing and turning, it's nothing
少年少女 戦国無双
Boys and girls, unparalleled in the warring states
浮世の随に
Following the fleeting world
千本桜 夜に紛れ
A thousand cherry trees, blending into the night
君の声も届かないよ
Even your voice won't reach me
此処は宴 鋼の檻
Here is a feast, a cage of steel
その断頭台を飛び降りて
Jump down from that guillotine
千本桜 夜に紛れ
A thousand cherry trees, blending into the night
君が歌い 僕は踊る
You sing, and I will dance
此処は宴 鋼の檻
Here is a feast, a cage of steel
さあ光線銃を撃ちまくれ
Now, fire that ray gun like crazy
改めて、あけましておめでとうございます！
Happy New Year, once again!
お正月ということで...
Since it's New Year's...
...振袖で登場しちゃいました。
...I've appeared in my furisode.
いかがですか？振袖。
How do you like the furisode?
去年の新年の新聞でね...
This is the kimono I was wearing...
...着ていた着物になります。
...in last year's New Year's newspaper.
なんかこうやって実際に着物着てみると...
Wearing a kimono in person like this...
...ちょっと、なんか身が引き締まる思いですね。
...really makes me feel a bit more composed.
そして、ステージも見てください！
And please, look at the stage!
こんなに豪華なステージがあるんですよ。
There's such a magnificent stage here.
あっち、見に行きましょう、あっち。
Let's go over there and take a look.
こちらには、今年がね...
Over here, since this year...
...うさぎ年ということで...
...is the Year of the Rabbit...
...うさぎの、なんか飛んでるうさぎさんがいたりとか。
...there are things like these flying bunnies.
後ろの金屏風には富士山が描いてあったりとか。
And Mount Fuji is painted on the golden folding screen behind me.
あとは、綺麗なお花。
Plus, there are beautiful flowers.
あと、門松。
And Kadomatsu.
門松はね、あっち側にもあるんですよ。見てください。
There's another Kadomatsu over on that side, too. Take a look.
立派な木もありますね。
There's also a grand tree.
こんな感じでなんかもう「お正月おめでたいね」っていう感じの...
It's a stage that really gives off...
...ステージになってます。
...that festive 'Happy New Year' feeling.
上にはね、迎春って書いてあるんだよ。ほら！
On top, it says 'Geishun' (Welcome Spring). Look!
みんなも... あ！だるま！
Everyone... Oh! A Daruma!
だるまのうさぎさんもいる！可愛い！
There's a Daruma rabbit too! So cute!
素敵なね、お正月のステージ。ありがとうございます。
Thank you for this wonderful New Year's stage.
いやー...。そして、この装い... 洋服ではないんですけど...
Well... And this outfit... it's not Western clothes, but...
...この格好。覚えてますか？
...do you remember this look?
こういう感じで新聞に載っておりました。
This is how I appeared in the newspaper.
あん肝も、あん肝も今とっても喜んでるよ。
Ankimo is also very happy right now.
「ボクもお正月に出れたよー」って喜んでる。
He's happy, saying, 'I got to appear for New Year's too!'
そして、この... 後ろとかもちょっと見てみましょう。
And let's take a look at the back too.
帯がね、こういう感じですごく...
The obi is like this, and it's quite...
...ちょっとね、大人っぽいものになっていたりとか。
...it's a bit of a more mature design.
ま、柄はね、やっぱお花になっていて、下のほうからだんだん...
Well, the pattern is flowers, of course, starting from the bottom and gradually...
あとなんか明るくなっていくような色合いになってるんで、
And since the colors seem to get brighter like this,
髪飾りもとっても可愛くて、
the hair ornaments are also very cute,
なんだかこんな振袖で1月1日を始められて、
and being able to start January 1st in a furisode like this
とっても嬉しく思っています。
makes me feel very happy.
そして、ホロライブは今年5周年を迎えています。
And Hololive is celebrating its 5th anniversary this year.
4、5年前はね、まさか振袖を着れるようになるとは思わず、
Four or five years ago, I never thought I'd be able to wear a furisode,
言ったことあるんですけど、袖がなかったみたいな。
I've said this before, but it's like I didn't even have sleeves.
袖のない振袖だったのがね、5年経って、
It used to be a sleeveless furisode, but after five years,
ちゃんと振袖をこうやって着れるようになったり、
I'm finally able to wear a proper furisode like this,
そしてね、仲間がたくさん増えて、こんなに素敵なスタッフさんたちと
and with so many more friends now, and such wonderful staff members,
素敵な番組を作れるようになりました。
we're able to make wonderful programs like this.
本当にそれは皆さんの応援があるからだなと思います。
I truly believe it's all thanks to everyone's support.
これからも私たちは頑張っていくので、
We'll continue to do our best,
私もホロライブをよろしくお願いします。
so please continue to support me and Hololive.
さてさて！
Now then!
新年ということで、嬉しいお知らせもいっぱいしていけたらいいなと思いますよ！
Since it's the New Year, I'd like to share lots of exciting announcements!
では、いきますね。
Here we go.
まずは、こちら！
First up, this!
今年は卯年ということで、ぺこらちゃんが何か良からぬことを考えてるみたい。
This year is the Year of the Rabbit, and it seems Pekora-chan is plotting something mischievous.
その名も、#全人類兎化計画！
It's called: #AllHumanityRabbitificationPlan!
一体何が始まるんだろう？
I wonder what's going to happen?
こちらは本日1月1日夜19時からホロライブ公式チャンネルにて配信予定です。
This is scheduled to be streamed on the official Hololive channel today, January 1st, from 7:00 PM.
みんな19時の予定は空けとくんですよ！
Everyone, make sure to keep your schedule free at 7:00 PM!
続いては、こちら！
Next, this!
1月13日金曜日、pixiv様とホロライブクリエイターコンテスト2023を開催します。
On Friday, January 13th, we will hold the Hololive Creator Contest 2023 with pixiv.
ホロライブをテーマにしたイラスト、水着衣装デザイン、シナリオの3点を
We'll be accepting entries for Hololive-themed illustrations, swimsuit designs, and scenarios
クリエイターの皆様に約1ヶ月募集させていただきます。
from all you creators for about a month.
詳細は1月13日の公式ツイートをご確認ください。
Please check the official tweet on January 13th for details.
続いては、こちら！
Next, this!
過去ホロライブメンバーが出演したホロライブアイドルプロジェクトファーストライブ
The 'hololive IDOL PROJECT 1st Live,
「Bloom,」が現在ABEMAで放映中です。
Bloom,' featuring Hololive members, is currently broadcasting on ABEMA.
Bloom,を見てくれた人も見たことがない人も、この機会にぜひチェックしてみてください。
Whether you've seen 'Bloom,' before or not, please take this opportunity to check it out.
詳細はABEMAのホームページで検索してみてね。
Search on the ABEMA website for details.
続いては、こちら！
Next, this!
明日、1月2日にみこちのお正月衣装お披露目もあるよ！
Tomorrow, January 2nd, Mikochi will have her New Year's outfit reveal!
どうやら色んな企画を用意してるみたいだから、みんなチェックしてみてね！
It looks like she has various projects prepared, so everyone, check it out!
そしてそして！続いては、こちら！
And also! Next, this!
星街すいせいセカンドアルバム「SPECTER」、1月25日水曜日、発売決定！おめでとう！
Hoshimachi Suisei's 2nd Album 'SPECTER' will be released on Wednesday, January 25th! Congratulations!
セカンドアルバムとなる今作では、Ayase、じん、田淵智也、
This second album features 11 songs written by a talented lineup,
ナナホシ管弦楽団ら豪華クリエイター陣が書き下ろした全11曲を収録した作品となっています。
including Ayase, Jin, Tomoya Tabuchi, and Nanahoshi Orchestra.
現在予約受付中！
Pre-orders are now open!
さらに、星街すいせいセカンドソロライブ「Shout in Crisis」、
Furthermore, Hoshimachi Suisei's 2nd Solo Live 'Shout in Crisis' will be held
2023年1月28日土曜日に東京ガーデンシアターにて開催！
at Tokyo Garden Theater on Saturday, January 28, 2023!
現在SPWNにて配信チケット発売中！
Streaming tickets are now on sale at SPWN!
詳しくは各種公式サイトをご確認ください。
Please check the various official websites for details.
さて、続いては、こちら！
Now, next is this!
今年も常闇トワさん主催の「ホロお正月カップ」を開催します！
This year, we will again hold the 'Holo New Year Cup' hosted by Tokoyami Towa-san!
今年の最強は誰の手に？みんな楽しみだね！
Who will be the strongest this year? Everyone's looking forward to it!
そして、ザコ杯の優勝者は？
And who will be the champion of the Zako Cup?
ぜひ皆さんチェックしてくださいね。
Everyone, please check it out.
そしてそして、たくさんあった告知もいよいよ最後です！最後は、こちら！
And finally, the last of our many announcements! The last one is this!
1月5日お昼頃から、友人Aちゃんと春先のどかちゃんのホロライブスタッフコンビで
Around noon on January 5th, the Hololive staff duo, Friend A-chan and Harusaki Nodoka-chan,
年末年始の振り返り配信を実施します！
will hold a recap stream of the year-end and New Year holidays!
ゆくホロくるホロやカウントダウンライブなどなど、スタッフ視点での裏話も！
They'll share behind-the-scenes stories from a staff perspective about 'Yuku Holo Kuru Holo,' the countdown live, and more!
年末年始の情報はこの放送でバッチリ押さえちゃいましょう！
Let's catch up on all the year-end and New Year info in this broadcast!
詳細は二人のTwitterを見てね！
Check their Twitter for details!
1月5日 お昼ごろ
怒涛の年末年始 振り返り放送
[出演] 友人A 春先のどか
January 5th around noon
A frantic year-end/New Year review broadcast
[Cast] Friend A, Harusaki Nodoka
というわけで、本年も
And so, this year as well,
ホロライブプロダクションを
we hope you'll continue to support
どうぞよろしくお願いします！
Hololive Production!
hololive production COUNTDOWN LIVE 2022-2023 -hololive side-